Autograph File, B: Guide.
Autograph File, B,
- Breitkopf Härtel, Leipzig. A list of the contents of 5 cases of manuscripts... hidden during the war by Hellmuth von Hase. TS.; Leipzig, Jun 1945., 5s.(9p.)
  With additional material.
  Recat. fr. XLB 636F.
- Bremen, Meyer von. A.L.s.to Messrs Williams; Everett; Berlin, 3 Feb 1872., 1s.(1p.)
- Bremer, Frederika, 1801-1865. A.L.s. to Rebecca Spring; [Boston?] 25 Feb [1850], 2s.(2p.)
  *44M-65. Presented by Walter Stone Poor, Esq., 12 July 1944.
- Bremer, Fredrika, 1801-1865. A.L.s.to David Osgood; Rome, 26 Jan 1858., 1s.(4p.)
- Bremer, Fredrika, 1801-1865. A.L.s.to Maria (White) Lowell; Gotheborg, 13 Aug 1853., 1s.(3p.)
- Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924. Watercolor drawing of butterfly, with A.signature; [n.p.,n.d.]
- Brenner, Victor David, 1871-1924. A.signature; [New York, n.d.]
- Brent, Charles Henry, bp., 1862-1929. 2 A.L.s.to Robert Bacon and Mrs Bacon:
  - Paris, 20 Mar 1918., 2s.(2p.)
  - Tarnesda, 5 Jul 1919., 1s.(4p.)
- Brent, Daniel, 1774-1841. MS.L.s. to Edward Everett; Washington, 10 Apr 1832., 1s.(3p.)
  *50M-179. Presented by Richard L. Freeman, Esq., Nov 1950.
- Brent, Daniel, 1774-1841. MS.L.s. to William Beach Lawrence; Washington, 8 Jul 1826., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181 (315). Gift of J. F. Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Brentano, Clemens, 1778-1842. A.MS.s.(facsimile) poem; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bréquigny, Louis Georges Oudart-Feudrix de, 1714-1795. A.L.s. to [ ] Mercier de St. Léger; [n.p.] 22 Aug 1780., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (48). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Brereton, Robert A.L.s.to Metton Mowbray; London, Apr 1836., 1s.(1p.)
- Breshko-Breshkovskaia, Ekaterina Konstantinovna (Verigo) 1844-1934. A.L.s.(postcard) to [Mrs John C.] Lee; Prague, 28 Feb 1924., 1s.(1p.)
- Breshko-Breshkovskaia, Ekaterina Konstantinovna (Verigo) 1844-1934. A.L.s.to [Mrs Robert Gould] Shaw; Prague, 25 Feb 1923., 1s.(1p.) [postcard]
- Brevoort, James Carson, 1818-1887. A.L.s.to [ ] Harrison; Brooklyn, 12 Mar 1883., 1s.(2p.)
- Brewer, William Henry, 1828-1910. A.L.s.to Andrew Johnson; New Haven, 18 Jul 1867., 1s.(2p.)
- Brewster, Anne Maria Hampton, b. 1818. 3 A.L.s.to [ ] Dwight:
  - Bridgeton, 20 Jan 1863., 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 21 Jan 1866., 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 12 Mar 1866., 1s.(2p.)
- Brewster, Benjamin Harris, 1816-1888. A.L.s.to [ ]; [ ? ] 26 Feb 1880., 1s.(1p.)
- Brewster, Benjamin A.L.s.to Am. Ch. Almanac; Grand Junction, 17 Nov 1912., 1s.(1p.)
- Brewster, Sir David, 1781-1868. A.L.s. to Parker Cleaveland; St. Andrews, 1 Nov 1845., 1s.(4p.)
- Brewster, Sir David, 1781-1868. A.L.s. to Thomas Cadell; Allerly by Melrose, 2 Jun 1831., 1s.(3p.)
  With printed matter.
  *78M-10. Gift of Mrs. Detlev Bronk, Jan 1979.
- Brewster, G. Douglas A.L.s.to Benjamin W. Austin; New York 16 Feb 1893., 1s.(1p.)
- Březina, Otokar, pseud., 1868-1929. A.L.s.to [Paul Selver]; Jaroměřice, 6 Nov 1913., 1s.(1p.)
  *58M-73. Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund from F. C. I., 3 Dec 1958.
- Bridell, Frederick Lee, 1831-1863. 3 A.L.s.to Henry Mogford:
  - Fitzroy Square, 5 May 1856., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 3 Nov 1856., 1s.(1p.)
  - Isleworth, 19 Nov 1856., 1s.(3p.)
- Bridge, John A.L.s.to John Jackson; Ludgate, 7 Sep 1825., 1s.(1p.)
- Bridges, James. A.L.s.to J H Graves; Oxford, 4 Oct 1837., 1s.(1p.)
- Bridges, John 2 A.L.s.to [ ]:
  - [London] 4 Apr 1836., 1s.(1p.)
  - [Same, 1839], 1s.(1p.)
- Bridges, John A.MS.s. list of paintings; [n.p., 1834], 1s.(1p.)
- Bridges, Mary Monica (Waterhouse) A.L.s. to John Lowes and Mary Lowes; Chilswell, 14 Dec 1931., 1s.(2p.)
  *46M-398. Purchased from the library of John Livingston Lowes, 13 Dec 1945.
- Bridges, Robert, 1844-1930. A.L.s.to Abbott Lawrence Lowell; Ann Arbor, 19 May 1924., 1s.(1p.)
- Bridges, W. A.L.s. to [ ] Mortimer; [Plymouth, 2 Oct 1842], 1s. (4p.)
  r.f.x5.15F*
- Bridges, W 2 A.L.s. to [ ]; 1842.
  - Plymouth, 13 Oct 1842., 2s. (6p.)
  - same, 9 Nov 1842., 4s. (6p.)
    Recat. fr. x5.16F*, 25 Sept 1928
- Bridgewater, John Egerton,2d earl of, 1622-1686. A.L.s.(initials;draft) to [Margaret (Lucas) Cavendish, duchess of Newcastle]; [n.p.,ca. 1662], 1s.(1p.)
  From *55-682. Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, 19 Dec 1955.
- Bridgford, J. W. A.L.s.to [ ]; [London][1839], 1s.(1p.)
- Bridgford, J. W. A.L.s.to H. Howard; [London] 5 Apr 1836., 1s.(1p.)
- Bridgman, Amy S. A.L.s.to Florence (Cushman) Milner; Portsmouth, [ ] 1915., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of Florence Milner, 1924.
- Bridgman, Laura Dewey, 1829-1889. A. signature; [n.p., 17 May 1855], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-499(16) Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Bridgman, Laura Dewey, 1829-1889. A.signature; [n.p.,n.d.]
- Bridgman, Thomas, 1795- A.L.(3d person) to [ ] Davis; Norwich, 5 Mar [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bridgman, William Henry, 1830- 2 ALs to Thomas Nast;1868 July 3 and 1868 Aug. 4., 2s.(4p.)
  Both letters include pencil sketches by Nast with his captions. Captions on the theme of women's rights include: "Men right [sic] meetings", "We want the vote", and "See to the men and children". Legible captions on the theme of city life include: "Street car - 'Take my seat'", and "Take that crying baby upstairs". Military-related captions include "Off to the war", and "7th Reg't".
  *43M-303-304. Gift of Cyril Nast, 1943 Nov. 20.
- Brifaut, Charles, 1781-1851. A.L.s. to [Claude Emmanuel Joseph Pierre, marquis de Pastoret]; Paris, 17 May [1826], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (49). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Briggs, Charles Augustus, 1841-1913. A.L.s.to John Nathan Cobb; [New York, Dec 1893], 1s.(1p.)
  On verso of J.N.C's letter to Briggs of 9 Dec 1893.
- Briggs, Charles Frederick, 1804-1877. A.L.s. to Frederick Goddard Tuckerman; New York, 13 Jun [185-], 1s.(2p.)
  *54M-209 (12) Presented by Orton Loring Clark, Mar 1955.
- Briggs, George Nixon, 1796-1861. Proclamation for fast day. A.MS.s.; Boston, 2 Mar 1846., 2s.(3p.)
- Briggs, George Nixon, 1796-1861. A.L.s. to William Henry Seward; Pittsfield, 16 Jan 1861., 1s.(1p.)
- Briggs, George Nixon, 1796-1861. A.L.s. to Joseph Grinnell; Boston, 27 Apr 1848., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1946. Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Briggs, George Nixon, 1796-1861. MS.L.(copy) to [Martha (Henshaw)] Bates; [Boston] 22 Mar 1845., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1947. Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Briggs, George Nixon, 1796-1861. A.L.s.to Walter S. Alexander; Pittsfield, 18 Dec 1852., 1s.(1p.)
- Briggs, H. S. A.L.s.to Andrew Atkinson Humphreys; Alexandria, 22 Feb 1864., 1s.(1p.)
  *60M-54 (3) In memory of E.S. Wallace, 13 Oct 1960.
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.L.s.to Emma Burton; [London?] 18 Nov 1842., 1s.(1p.) env.
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.L.(3d person) to Messrs. Colnaghi; [London?] 1 Mar 1838., 1s.(1p.)
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.L.s.to T. Lupton; [London?] [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.L.s.to H. R. Priest; Middlesex Hospital, 24 Oct 1835., 1s.(1p.)
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.L.s.to [ ] Vaughan; [n.p.] 30 Jul 1840., 1s.(1p.)
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. 3 A.lists of paintings to [ ]; Middlesex Hospital, [1839], 3s.(3p.)
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.list of pictures s. to Henry Howard; [London?] [n.d.], 2s.(3p.)
- Briggs, Henry Perronet, 1793-1844. A.signature on engraving; [n.p.,n.d.]
- Briggs, Le Baron Russell, 1855-1934. A.L.s. to [George Lyman] Paine; [Bournedale?] Nov 1923., 1s. (1p.)
  *71M-25. Purchased with the C.E. Norton fund, 8 July 1971.
- Briggs, Thomas A.L.s.to [ ] Simmons; [n.p.] 13 Sep 1783., 1s.(1p.)
- Brigham, Charles P. A.L.s.to John [ ]; San Francisco,1876., 1s.(1p.)
- Brigham, William 2 A.L.s.to Douglas Taylor:
  - [New York] 7 Feb 1896., 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 22 Jan 1896., 1s.( 2p.)
- Bright, John, 1811-1889. A.signature; [n.p.] 27 Dec 1886.
- Bright, John,1811-1889. [Pass to gallery, House of Commons] MS.s.; 8 May 1867.
  The signature, originally pencil, has been traced over in ink.
  *46M-326. Gift of Miss Lilian Page, 16 Nov 1946.
- Bright, John, 1811-1889. A.L.s.to Maurice Wakeman; London, 24 Jan 1855., 1s.(4p.)
- Bright, John, 1811-1889. A.L.s.(lithographic facsimile) to Henry Vincent; Rochdale, 19 Jul 1866., 1s.(3p.)
  *48M-224 (8) Presented by Mrs. Charles Lewis Slattery, 1 July 1948.
- Bright, John, 1811-1889. A.L.s.to [ ] Rabit; Rochdale, 8 Jun 1878., 1s.(1p.)
- Bright, John, 1783-1870. A.L.s.to Thomas Gibbons; [London] 21 Jun 1853., 1s.(1p.)
- Bright, John, 1811-1889. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 2 May 1849., 1s.(3p.)
- Brightwell, Celia Lucy, 1811-1875. A.L.s.to [Mrs ] Turner; [n.p.] 23 Apr 1845., 1s.(4p.)
- Brigstocke, Thomas, 1809-1881.
  - A.L.s.to [ ] Clements; Pimlico, 23 Feb 1843., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.to [ ] Braham; Pimlico [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Brigstocke, Thomas, 1809-1881. A.L.s.to Gaspare Conti; London, 22 Dec 1866., 1s.(2p.)
- Brigstocke, Thomas, 1809-1881. A.L.s.to [ ] Hodgson; Pimlico, 10 Apr 1843., 1s.(2p.)
- Brigstocke, Thomas, 1809-1881. A.L.s.to William Igguldon; London, 22 Dec 1844., 1s.(2p.)
- Brigstocke, Thomas, 1809-1881. A.L.s.to E. M. Ward; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Brimmer, Martin, 1829-1896. 4 A.L.s.to Waldo Higginson; 2-10 Mar 1890.
  On the establishment of the George B. Sohier Prize.
  Gift of Charles H. Taylor, 1924.
- Briston, George A.L.s.to; John G. Locke; Boston, 4 Aug 1836., 1s.(1p.)
- Bristowe, Edmund, 1787-1876. A.L.s.to [ ]; Windsor, 10 Jan 1820., 1s.(1p.)
- Brittany (France). États. Consulat de Nantes. Extrait des registres du greffe...du siege royal du consulat de Nantes: manuscript; 1764 Sept. 4., 1s.(4p.)
  In French. Concerns a judgement in a merchants' transaction involving indigo. With an official wax seal and stamp. Named parties include Francois Bazille de Chanteloup,; Margueritte Angelique Bazille,; André Chereau de Latouche, and Jean Charles Leroux Desrivellieres.
  *66M-204. Transferred from Radcliffe College, 1966 Sept.
- Britton, John, 1771-1857. A.L.s.to William Jerdan; [n.p.] 25 Apr 1832., 1s.(2p.)
- Britton, John, 1771-1857. 2 A.L.s.to Thomas Hill:
  - Tavistock, 2 Jan 1815., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 14 Feb 1815., 1s.(1p.)
- Britton, John, 1771-1857. A.L.s. to E[ ] Campbell; [London] 17 May 1836., 1s. (3p.)
  Removed from 12463.230.
- Britton, John, 1771-1857. A.L.s.to Robert Freebairn; [n.p.] 29 Mar 1846., 1s.(1p.)
- Broadley, Alexander Mayrick, 1847-1916. A.L.s.to [Charles Francis?] Keary; Bridport, 25 Dec 1904., 1s.(4p.)
  Mentions Edmund Yates.
  Gratis, n.d.
- Broch, Hermann, 1886-1951. 4 letters to Paul Amann:
  - T.L.s.; Princeton, 20 Jul 1943., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; same, 16 Oct 1943., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; same [8 Oct 1947], 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; same [15 Jul 1948], 1s.(2p.)
    *54M-257. Gift of Paul Amann, 22 June 1955.
- Brock, C.E. (Charles Edmund), 1870-1938, illustrator. Romances of foreign crime: the opportunity of Andrea Torres: drawing (signed), [ca. 1919-1920]., 1 drawing: ink on paper, 24 x 25 cm.
  Accompanying note indicates the drawing may have accompanied a short story intended for the magazine, Premier.
  *65M-230. Purchased from Elkin Mathews, 1966 21 May.
- Brockedon, William, 1787-1854. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brockedon, William, 1787-1854. 4 A.L.s.to [Abraham] Cooper:
  - [N.p.] 30 Apr 1829., 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p.] 30 Apr 1829., 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] 14 Dec 1851., 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] [n.d.], 1s.(3p.)
- Brockedon, William, 1787-1854. A.L.s.to R. Jennings; [n.p.] 2 Jul 1834., 1s.(1p.)
- Brockedon, William, 1787-1854. A.L.s.to [ ] Sims; [n.p.] 23 May [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brockedon, William, 1787-1854. A.L.s.to J. T. Smith; [n.p.] 8 Apr 1825., 1s.(1p.)
- Brockedon, William, 1787-1854. 3 A. picture lists s.; 1828,1834 1836., 3s.(3p.)
- Brockett, Linus Pierpont, 1820-1893. A.L.s.to R. E. Thompson; Brooklyn, 28 Dec 1882., 1s.(1p.)
- Brodie, Sir Benjamin Collins, bart., 1783-1862. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 23 Apr 1824., 1s.(1p.)
- Brodrick, George Charles, 1831-1903. A.L.s.to [Charles William] Eliot; Oxford, 29 Mar 1883., 2s.(8p.)
- Brodzinski, Kazimierz, 1791-1835. A.L.s. to Sir John Bowring; Varsovie, 4 Nov 1823., 1s.(3p.)
- Broglie, Albert, duc de, 1821-1901. A.L.s. to [ ]; Broglie, 18 Aug 1865., 1s.(3p.)
  *49M-187 (52) From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Broglie, Achille, duc de, 1785-1870. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 13 May 1851., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (50) From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Broglie, Achille, duc de, 1785-1870. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 9 Apr [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (51) From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Brohan, Haywood. MS.L.s. to Samuel Kennedy; Steamship "Mississippi", 5 Jul 1865., 1s. (3p.).
  Signed by 53 others.
  Removed from ALS file [n.s., n.d.]
- Broke, Sir Philip Bowes Vere, bart., 1776-1841. Partly printed D.s.; Greenwich, 26 Sep 1808., 1s.(1p.)
  *50M-595. Bequest of W.B.O. Field, 1951.
- Broke, Sir Philip Bowes Vere, bart., 1776-1841. MS.L.(3rd person) to [ ]; [n.p.] 8 Dec 1837., 1s.(3p.)
  *50M-594. Bequest of W.B.O. Field, 1951.
- Broke-Vere, Sir Charles MS.L.(3d person) to Duke of Wellington; [n.p.] 2 Jun 1826., 1s.(1p.)
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. [Agreement with N.B.C. for the broadcasting of a reading from My ninety acres]. TS.(mimeographed form) and TS., signed; New York, 9 Aug 1948., 1s.(1p.)
  *82M-45 (2) Gift of Mr. Daniel D. Chabris, Dec 1982.
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. 4 letters to Margaret Cuthbert,1944-1945., 1 folder
  Written to Cuthbert at the National Broadcasting Company and concerning a "World's Great Novel" series.
  *98M-18 Gift of Daniel Chabris, 1998 Sept. 23.
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. Autograph inscription to Mrs. L. R. Gurney; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
  With cut title-page from The rains came (1937).
  *82M-45 (3) Gift of Mr. Daniel D. Chabris, Dec 1982.
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. T.L.s. with A.MS. revisions to Harry [ ]; Lucas, Ohio, 25 Jan 1948., 4s.(4p.)
  *88M-34. Gift of Daniel D. Chabris, 12 May 1989.
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. A.L.s. to [ ] Munson; Senlis [n.d.]., 2s.(4p.)
  *89M-17. Gift of Daniel D. Chabris, through Ellis H. Neel, Jr., 4 Dec 1989.
- Bromfield, Louis, 1896-1956. A.L.s. to Edith Wharton; Senlis, [18 Mar 1934]., 2s.(4p.) env.
  *82M-45 (1) Gift of Mr. Daniel D. Chabris, Dec 1982.
- Bromley, Valentine Walter, 1848-1877. A.L.s.to [Benjamin Richard] Green; London, 14 Dec 1868., 1s.(2p.)
- Bronaugh, John W. A.L.s. to [William] Hull; George Town, 10 May 1812., 1s. (2p.)
  About Indian affairs.
- Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855. A.L.s. to [Sidney] Dobell; Haworth, 8 Dec 1850., 1s.(3p.) TS.
  Enclosed is T. description and explanation of letter.
  *52M-172. Presented by Mr. David Sidney Jensen, 18 Sept 1952.
- [Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855] MS.L.(contemporary copy?) to Ellen [Nussey]; [Haworth] 13 Jan 1832., 1s.(3p.)
  r.f. MS Eng 35F
  Bequest of Mrs. H.J. Bradbury, 26 June 1930.
- Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855. A.L. to Ellen Nussey; Haworth, May 1847., 3s. (4p.)
  Fragments.
- Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855. The trumpet hath sounded [first line] A.MS.s.; [Haworth] 11 Dec 1831., 1s.(3p.) TS.
  Enclosed is T. description and explanation of manuscript.
  *52M-173. Purchased from James F. Drake, 6 Feb 1953.
- Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855. A.L.s. to Lady [Janet] [Kay] Shuttleworth; Haworth, 5 Feb 1850., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-499(17) Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Brontë, Emily, 1818-1848. Drawing: The Whinchat. Pencil drawing, s.; [n.p.] 1 Apr 1829., 1s.(2p.)
  Copied by Emily Brontë from "A History of British Birds."
  *42M-499(18) Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Brontë, Patrick, 1777-1861. A.L.s.to [John?] Domnen; Haworth, 4 Mar 1857., 1s.(1p.)
  *43M-143F. Presented by Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Sept 1943.
- Brontë, Patrick Branwell, 1817-1848. MS.(facsimile); [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brooke, F. C. A.L.s.to [ ] Gorham; Oklahoma City, 6 Nov 1912., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooke, F. K. A.L.s.to [ ]; Oklahoma City [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brooke, F. K. A.L.s.to [ ]; Oklahoma City, 21 Nov 1912., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooke, John Charles, 1748-1794. A.L.s.to [ ]; Lausanne, 11 Aug 1763., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooke, John Rutter, 1838-1926. A.L.s.to Benjamin E. Hall; New York, 19 Oct 1908., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooke, Rupert, 1887-1915. 3 A.L.s.to [Mrs ] Graham:
  - Rugby, 18 Mar 1913., 1s.(3p.)
  - Same [23 Mar 1913], 1s.(4p.)
  - S.S.Cedric, May 1913., 1s.(3p.)
    *44M-141-143. Purchased from Stevens Brown, 10 Oct 1944.
- Brooke, Stopford Augustus, 1832-1916. A.L.s.to [Georgiana (Macdonald)] Burne-Jones; [London?] 17 Nov 1879., 1s.(1p.)
- Brookes, Charles Cunliffe. T.L.s. to Anthony Netboy; Steeple Aston, 26 Dec 1930., 4s.(4p.)
  Includes typed copies of a letter from John Henry Brookes to Walter Pater, and the reply; 29 and 31 Oct 1868.
  *51M-63. Gift of Anthony Netboy, 10 Aug 1951.
- Brookes, Charles Cunliffe. T.L.s. to Anthony Netboy; Steeple Aston, 23 Jan 1931., 3s.(4p.)
  Includes A.L.s. from George Herbert Tremenheere to Brookes; 1931.
  *51M-64. Gift of Anthony Netboy, 10 Aug 1951.
- Brookes, Joshua, 1761-1833. MS.L.(3d person) to [ ] Bickman; [London] 9 Apr 1817., 1s.(1p.)
- Brookes, Sophia, recipient. [2 anonymous valentines addressed to Miss Brookes] MS. and printed matter; [n.p., n.d.], 2s.(4p.)
  *44M-91. Presented by Walter Stone Poor, Esq., 12 July 1944.
- Brooks, Alfred A.L.s.to Solomon Lincoln; Medford, 15 May 1873., 1s.(1p.) env.
- Brooks, Charles, 1795-1872. A.L.s.to Caleb Bates; Paris, 18 Jul 1840., 1s.(3p.)
  Enclosing MS.L.s.by Victor Cousin, Ministère de l'instruction publique; Paris, 7 Jul 1840. 1s. (1p.)
  Gift of Mrs. M. A. Potter, 1930.
- Brooks, Charles, 1795-1872. 2 A.L.s.to Caleb Bates:
  - Paris, 17 Jan 1840., 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 30 Dec 1841., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Charles, 1795-1872. A.L.s.to Solomon Lincoln; Medford, 18 Mar 1862., 1s.(4p.) env.
- Brooks, Charles, 1795-1872. MS.(unsigned) report on 2 printed examination forms; [n.p.,n.d.], 5s. (5p.)
  Gift of Mrs. F.D. Haddock, 1936.
- Brooks, Charles, 1795-1872. Printed letter to members of Board of Examiners, Harvard College; Boston, 9 Mar 1848., 1s.(2p.)
  Gift of Mrs. F. D. Haddock, 1936.
- Brooks, Charles, 1795-1872. [Miscellaneous MS. material pertaining to Charles Brooks]; [v.p.,v.d.], 9 pieces.
- Brooks, Charles Timothy, 1813-1883. A.L.s. to [Caleb Davis?] Bradlee; Newport, 9 Sep 1872., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1948. Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Brooks, Charles Timothy, 1813-1883. Letters to John S. Dwight:
  - [ ? ] 20 Aug 1833., 1s.(1p.)
  - Cambridge, 12 Mar 1834., 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 20 Jan 1834., 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 26 May 1834., 1s.(4p.)
  - Windsor,Vt., 11 Jul 1836., 1s.(4p.)
  - Salem, 26 Oct 1836., 1s.(3p.)
  - Newport, 30 Jan 1837., 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 11 May 1837., 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 10 Oct 1837., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 12 Apr 1838., 1s.(3p.)
  - Newport, 24 Dec 1838., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 7 Jan 1839., 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 9 Jul 1841., 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 14 May 1856., 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 14 Jul 1868., 1s.(2p.)
  - Newport, 26 Jul 1868., 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 23 Sep 1872., 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 2 Feb 1876., 1s.(3p.)
- Brooks, Charles Timothy, 1813-1883. A.L.s. to [ ]; Newport, 9 Aug 1861., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(70) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Brooks, Charles Timothy, 1813-1883. The burial of Charles V. A.MS.s.; Newport, 16 Jun 1880., 1s. (1p.)
- Brooks, Elbridge Streeter, 1846-1902. From verses "For Decoration Day" ... A.MS.s.; Somerville, 1 Feb 1894., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooks, James, 1810-1873. A. signature; Washington, Mar 1867., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooks, John, 1752-1825. A.L.s. to Jonathan Jackson; Medford, 23 Feb 1798., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1949. Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Brooks, John, 1752-1825. A.L.s.to Ezra Starkweather; Medford, 22 Aug 1800., 1s.(1p.)
  No date or source
- Brooks, John, 1752-1825. A.L.s.(copy) to [Captain ] Stone; Boston, 9 Aug 1786., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, John Graham, 1846-1938. A.L.s.(postcard) to Daniel Evans; [Portland, 13 Sep 1922], 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of J.G. Brooks, 1939.
- Brooks, Mary Louise 4 A.L.s.to [Adam] Badeau:
  - [N.p.] 15 Mar [1863], 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Newport] 19 Aug [1863], 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [N.p., 1863], 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [N.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Mary Louise A.L.s.to [Mrs ] Lincoln; New York, 21 Apr [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Nathan A.L.s.to Albert Locke; Concord, 12 Feb 1839., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s.to Constance [ ]; Boston, 3 Mar 1892., 1s.(3p.)
  Gift of Mrs. Clarence C. Williams, 1940.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s.(copy) to [ ]; [Boston] 1 Mar 1881., 1s.(1p.)
  *78M-26. Gift of William Bentinck-Smith, 16 Apr 1979.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.(3rd person) to [ ]; Boston, 2 Jul 1888., 1s.(1p.)
  *51M-163. Presented by John Francis Gough, Esq., 14 Feb 1952.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to Charles L. Andrews; [Boston] 12 Jun 1879., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [ ] Brigham; Boston, 8 Dec 1873., 2s.(2p.)
  *51M-166. Presented by John Francis Gough, Esq., 14 Feb 1952.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s.to [Wolcott] Calkins; Boston, 10 Nov 1892., 1s.(4p.)
  *61M-75. Gift of Rev. Raymond Calkins, 16 Aug 1961.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Philadelphia, 24 Jan 1888., 1s.(3p.)
  *45M-46. Presented by Miss Sylvia Annable, 24 Sept 1945.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 2 Feb 1889., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 8 Apr 1890., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 25 Mar 1891., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 18 May 1891., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 17 Oct 1891., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 25 Dec 1891., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; St. Moritz, 10 Aug 1892., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Baltimore, 24 Oct 1892., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Venice, 13 Aug 1882., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. 4 letters to Lorin Fuller Deland;1884-1893.
  *47M-93. Presented by Miss Sylvia Annable, 15 Nov 1947.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A .L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Interlaken, 12 Aug 1885., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 6 Jan 1886., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; on shipboard, 3 Jun 1886., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 31 Jan 1887., 1s.(1p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 4 Feb 1887., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller] Deland; Boston, 12 Apr 1887., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Lorin Fuller Deland]; Boston, 23 Jan 1882., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 23 Mar 1886., 1s.(3p.)
  *45M-45. Presented by Miss Sylvia Annable, 24 Sept 1945.
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 6 Dec 1886., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 27 Jan 1887., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 14 Mar 1887., 1s.(4p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 14 Apr 1887., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 19 Sep 1890., 1s.(2p.)
- Brooks, Phillips, bp., 1835-1893. A.L.s. to [Margaret (Campbell)] Deland; Boston, 19 Nov 1892., 1s.(1p.)